<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>new religious movements on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/new-religious-movements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in new religious movements on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/new-religious-movements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Diamond Approach</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/the-diamond-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/the-diamond-approach/</guid>
      <description>You can find out more here: https://www.diamondapproach.org/home</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inform</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/inform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/inform/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cults</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/cults/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/cults/</guid>
      <description>Introduction One of the key aspects of religion – particularly in public discourse – is the relationship between &amp;lsquo;organised religion&amp;rsquo; and small groups of devotees lead by charismatic individuals, commonly referred to as cults.
The term &amp;lsquo;cult&amp;rsquo; has a somewhat negative connotation, and conjures images of people submitting to a strange and dangerous pattern of behaviour.
We can see an example of this view in the US television series American Horror Story: Cult, in which a charismatic young man leads a group of disaffected individuals on a progressively more violent campaign to gain political power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The International Church of Cannabis</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/international-church-of-cannabis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/international-church-of-cannabis/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The International Church of Cannabis is a religious group based in Denver, Colorado, USA, which uses cannabis during its ceremonies in order to help members have a better understanding of themselves.
The church is unaffiliated with any other religious traditions, but its members are not restricted in any way - the church is viewed as a supplement to, rather than a replacement for, a person’s religious identity.
 &amp;hellip;there is no need to convert to Elevationism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caodaism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/caodaism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/caodaism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction At less than a century old, the Cao Dai religion (also known as Caodaism) is arguably a New Religious Movement. It emerged in Vietnam during the 1920s and based its structure on that of the Roman Catholic Church, but drew its principles and practices from Buddhism, Daoism, Christianity, and Confucianism (religious systems all alive in Vietnam at that time).
The tradition is traced back to Ngô Văn Chiêu, a Vietnamese official in the French colonial administration, who was particularly interested in religion and spiritualism (contact with the dead).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rizalism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/rizalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/rizalism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Filipino author José Rizal, who lived during the late 19th century, was a prominent nationalist voice in a period where the Philippine public was pushing for independence from their colonial rulers, Spain. Although he was not personally involved in the Philippine Revolution, his writings were nonetheless found to have been too controversial, contributing in part to the revolution, and he was therefore executed by the Spanish.
Rizal has since been elevated to the status of national hero amongst the Philippines, but for some his importance goes further, and they believe that his non-violent message of love and independence, rooted in Christianity and terminated by execution, was part of a second coming of Jesus Christ – others identify him with a pre-Spanish deity, or consider him a prophet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
