<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Main Pages on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/m/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Main Pages on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/m/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About the project</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/m/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/m/about/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Understanding Religion is a website that aims to provide easy access to information about the study of religion, published by the Online Centre for Religious Studies.
Always free, written clearly for a wide audience, grounded in academic study and supported by references for those who want to dive deeper.
It draws inspiration from a wide variety of online resources - notably Wikipedia, but also Harvard University&amp;rsquo;s Pluralism Project and the essays and resources published by REOnline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms and Conditions</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/m/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/m/terms/</guid>
      <description>If you use this site&amp;hellip; You&amp;rsquo;re responsible for your own computer, drive safely.
If you submit content&amp;hellip; You agree to share your material (including written articles or other media content) on the same basis that the site operates - i.e. Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International (CC BY-SA 4.0).
Accuracy of content&amp;hellip; We aim to not only provide accurate content, but to include references to academic sources to support and substantiate our articles. However, we can&amp;rsquo;t absolutely guarantee that everything on the site is correct, you should always take care to double-check or investigate if you&amp;rsquo;re unsure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>