<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ritual on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/ritual/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ritual on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 07:40:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/ritual/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BRIC-19</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/bric-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 07:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/bric-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robin Horton</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/robin-horton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/robin-horton/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Robin Horton (1932 - 2019), an English social anthropologist and philosopher, has carried out specialised study in comparative religion since the 1950s which has challenged and expanded views in the study of the anthropology of religion. He is notable for his comparison of traditional thought systems (including religion) to Western science.
Wikipedia
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catherine Bell</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/catherine-bell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/catherine-bell/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Catherine Bell (1953 – 23 May 2008) was an American religious studies scholar who specialised in the study of Chinese religions and ritual studies. From 1985 until her death she worked at Santa Clara University&amp;rsquo;s religious studies department, of which she was chair from 2000 to 2005.
Wikipedia
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimitris Xygalatas</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/dimitris-xygalatas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/dimitris-xygalatas/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  I am an anthropologist and cognitive scientist studying ritual, cooperation, and some of the things that make us human.
After receiving my PhD from the Institute of Cognition and Culture at Queen’s University Belfast, I held positions at the universities of Princeton, Aarhus, and Masaryk, where I served as Director of the Laboratory for the Experimental Research of Religion (LEVYNA). In 2014, I joined the University of Connecticut, where I direct the Experimental Anthropology Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ritual</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ritual/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Religious practices include a wide variety of activity, but in some cases these practices might be described as rituals, a term that carries many conflicting associations. We can look at ritual as a type of religious practice, which pays attention to not only what is done, but also the broader context in which the action is situated.
In other words, rituals are religious practices with some degree of specificity that separates them from ‘everyday’ religious activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronald Grimes</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ronald-grimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ronald-grimes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Ron Grimes is co-editor of the Oxford Ritual Studies Series, Director of Ritual Studies International, and the author of several books on ritual, including The Craft of Ritual Studies. He is Professor Emeritus in the Department of Religion and Culture at Wilfrid Laurier University in Waterloo, Canada. He has held the following positions: Senior Researcher and Senior Lecturer at Yale University; Visiting Professor of Religious Studies at Charles University in Prague; and Chair of Ritual Studies at Radboud University in the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>