<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Questions on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/categories/questions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Questions on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/categories/questions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is religious studies?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-studies/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Religious studies is the academic study of religion - but what does that really mean?
It means that we use scholarly tools and techniques to investigate what religion is, how it&amp;rsquo;s performed, why it exists, and what it means for the people who practice it.
It also means looking critically at how we build up our picture of ‘religion’ - who gets to define the category? What does it include, and what does it leave out?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who creates religion?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/who-creates-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/who-creates-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The modern study of religion, beginning in the 19th Century, has been traditionally driven by male European scholars, who have carried their own cultural biases and assumptions - some unconscious, others less so.
Until recently, there had been little awareness of these assumptions, and this had affected the ideas and methods used by academics; naturally we will have to negotiate some of these potential pitfalls if we want to build a more comprehensive and accurate picture of religion in the modern world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is religious literacy?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-literacy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Religious literacy is a term that has become more popular in recent years, but what exactly do we mean when we talk about it?
The word &amp;lsquo;literacy&amp;rsquo; definitely sounds like it has something to do with reading and understanding written texts - religious traditions will often (but not always!) write things down, so is religious literacy the ability to read these texts?
Nope!
Just like how being able to read is a skill that you can apply throughout your life, religious literacy is a skill that allows you to understand and interpret religious phenomena wherever you encounter them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes a place sacred?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-makes-a-place-sacred/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-makes-a-place-sacred/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To claim that a location, structure, or geographical feature is sacred is to assert that it is &amp;lsquo;&amp;hellip;set apart and regarded with special reverence&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; (Wolffe, 2017(a), p.213). Yet there are many ways to understand this sacrality, where it comes from, and how it is expressed by different groups of people. The term sacred has a strong religious association, and usually means that something serves a religious function, or holds importance for people by virtue of its religious associations (Oxford University Press, 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is religion?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religion/</guid>
      <description>The first step in the study of any subject is to define our terms, draw a line around the area we’re interested in, and decide how we’ll investigate.
Just like any other subject, the method of investigation will influence the type of results we achieve.
To borrow a metaphor from the world of science: if we use a telescope, we only see things that are large and far away; if we use a microscope, we only see things that are small and close.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
