<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>religious studies on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/religious-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in religious studies on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/religious-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Research on Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/critical-research-on-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/critical-research-on-religion/</guid>
      <description>Link You can access the journal here: https://journals.sagepub.com/home/crr</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal for the Study of Religious Experience (JSRE)</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/journal-for-the-study-of-religious-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/journal-for-the-study-of-religious-experience/</guid>
      <description>Link You can access the journal here: https://rerc-journal.tsd.ac.uk/index.php/religiousexp/index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religions</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/religions-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/religions-journal/</guid>
      <description>Link You can access the journal here: https://www.mdpi.com/journal/religions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Global Philosophy of Religion Project</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/global-philosophy-of-religion-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/global-philosophy-of-religion-project/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A project led by Professor Yujin Nagasawa and hosted by the Birmingham Centre for Philosophy of Religion in the School of Philosophy, Theology and Religion at the University of Birmingham.
The project aims to promote research into underrepresented regions and religious traditions from around the globe.
Link You can access the site here: https://www.global-philosophy.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBC Bitesize</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/bbc-bitesize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/bbc-bitesize/</guid>
      <description>Introduction BBC Bitesize is a learning resource for UK students of all ages, with revision guides and learning materials on a variety of topics - including religion.
Link You can access the site here: https://www.bbc.co.uk/bitesize</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBC Teach</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/bbc-teach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/bbc-teach/</guid>
      <description>Introduction BBC Teach is a resource for UK teachers of all age groups, with materials on a variety of topics - including religion.
Link You can access the site here: https://www.bbc.co.uk/teach</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Dimensions of Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/seven-dimensions-of-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/seven-dimensions-of-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The seven dimensions of religion are a framework for exploring and understanding religion, developed by the Scottish scholar of religion, Ninian Smart.
Smart&amp;rsquo;s approach sidestepped the issue of agreeing on what counted as &amp;lsquo;a religion&amp;rsquo;, and instead identified types of experience and expression that were demonstrably religious or spiritual in nature.
This modular approach to religious studies facilitated a much broader scope to consider and compare spiritual traditions and artefacts from around the world that may not have aligned with a Western conception of what a religion was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Varieties of Religious Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/the-varieties-of-religious-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/the-varieties-of-religious-experience/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Published at the beginning of the twentieth century, The Varieties of Religious Experience is a far-ranging exploration of the psychology and philosophy behind different kinds of religious experiences.
This edition features an introduction by Martin E. Marty.
In the sections below the book&amp;rsquo;s contents will be outlined and reviewed.
A copy of the text (albeit in a different edition) is available via Project Gutenberg here: https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/621
Commentary Lecture I - Religion and Neurology Pages 1-25</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is religious studies?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-studies/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Religious studies is the academic study of religion - but what does that really mean?
It means that we use scholarly tools and techniques to investigate what religion is, how it&amp;rsquo;s performed, why it exists, and what it means for the people who practice it.
It also means looking critically at how we build up our picture of ‘religion’ - who gets to define the category? What does it include, and what does it leave out?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who creates religion?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/who-creates-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/who-creates-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The modern study of religion, beginning in the 19th Century, has been traditionally driven by male European scholars, who have carried their own cultural biases and assumptions - some unconscious, others less so.
Until recently, there had been little awareness of these assumptions, and this had affected the ideas and methods used by academics; naturally we will have to negotiate some of these potential pitfalls if we want to build a more comprehensive and accurate picture of religion in the modern world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/lets-talk-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/lets-talk-religion/</guid>
      <description>Link You can access the channel here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9dRb4fbJQIbQ3KHJZF_z0g</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion for Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/religion-for-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/religion-for-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Link You can access the channel here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCct9aR7HC79Cv2g-9oDOTLw</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Religions Paradigm</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/world-religions-paradigm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/world-religions-paradigm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When the category of religion is used to describe &amp;lsquo;world religions&amp;rsquo;, it is often in a way that turns multiple diverse traditions, philosophies, and practices, into one single entity for the sake of simplicity.
A good example of this is Hinduism, which is a label coined by the British to describe the religion of the Indian people.
The hidden diversity of Hinduism
Hinduism did not exist in the language of the Indian peoples (in fact there are many languages in use on the Indian subcontinent); it was a label applied by British observers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BASR 2020 Worldviews in RS and RE Panel</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/basr-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/basr-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  This panel, curated by Wendy Dossett (University of Chester), discusses the Commission for Religious Education’s proposal for a shift towards studying “Religion and Worldviews” in Secondary Religious Education. Contributions from Wendy Dossett, Rudi Eliott Lockhart (former CEO of the Religious Education Council of England and Wales), Suzanne Owen (Leeds Trinity University), Paul-Francois Tremlett (Open University) and Malory Nye (Independent Academic affiliated to University of Glasgow).
 Link You can access the video here: www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rejected Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/rejected-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/rejected-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  What is meant by &amp;ldquo;rejected&amp;rdquo; in Rejected Religion? Put simply, it&amp;rsquo;s everything that has been considered &amp;lsquo;heretical&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;forbidden&amp;rsquo; by the dominant religions throughout Western history. Think of terms such as &amp;lsquo;the occult&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;the esoteric&amp;rsquo; and all that can be located in that area - magical practices such as witchcraft; alternate worldviews such as Satanism; systems such as astrology and tarot; the use of hallucinogenic substances for &amp;lsquo;spiritual&amp;rsquo; growth; or well-known people such as Aleister Crowley &amp;ndash; this is just a small sample of the larger &amp;lsquo;esoteric&amp;rsquo; category that this platform addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journal of Religion, Nature and Culture</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/journal-religion-nature-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/journal-religion-nature-culture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Link You can access the journal here: https://journals.equinoxpub.com/index.php/JSRNC/index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Religion Matters: Religious Literacy, Culture and Diversity</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/why-religion-matters-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/why-religion-matters-course/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Link You can access the course here: https://www.futurelearn.com/courses/why-religion-matters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is religious literacy?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-literacy/</guid>
      <description>Religious literacy is a term that has become more popular in recent years, but what exactly do we mean when we talk about it?
The word &amp;lsquo;literacy&amp;rsquo; definitely sounds like it has something to do with reading and understanding written texts - religious traditions will often (but not always!) write things down, so is religious literacy the ability to read these texts?
Nope!
Just like how being able to read is a skill that you can apply throughout your life, religious literacy is a skill that allows you to understand and interpret religious phenomena wherever you encounter them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ninian Smart</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ninian-smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ninian-smart/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Smart was a Scottish writer and educator who developed the field of academic religious studies, and helped to distance it from theology. He took the investigation away from which religion was &amp;lsquo;true&amp;rsquo;, and instead looked at the lived experiences of religious adherents.
Smart identified seven categories that could be used to break up the study of religion into focused areas; he called these the seven dimensions of religion.
 Doctrinal Mythological Ethical Ritual Experiential Institutional Material  You can remember them using this mnemonic device:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing World Religions</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/introducing-world-religions-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/introducing-world-religions-2008/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Religion: An Introduction to Key Ideas and Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/the-study-of-religion-an-introduction-to-key-ideas-and-methods-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/the-study-of-religion-an-introduction-to-key-ideas-and-methods-2007/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>