<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>religious studies on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/religious-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in religious studies on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/religious-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is religious studies?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-studies/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Religious studies is the academic study of religion - but what does that really mean?
It means that we use scholarly tools and techniques to investigate what religion is, how it&amp;rsquo;s performed, why it exists, and what it means for the people who practice it.
It also means looking critically at how we build up our picture of ‘religion’ - who gets to define the category? What does it include, and what does it leave out?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who creates religion?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/who-creates-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/who-creates-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The modern study of religion, beginning in the 19th Century, has been traditionally driven by male European scholars, who have carried their own cultural biases and assumptions - some unconscious, others less so.
Until recently, there had been little awareness of these assumptions, and this had affected the ideas and methods used by academics; naturally we will have to negotiate some of these potential pitfalls if we want to build a more comprehensive and accurate picture of religion in the modern world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/lets-talk-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/lets-talk-religion/</guid>
      <description>Link You can access the channel here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9dRb4fbJQIbQ3KHJZF_z0g</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religion for Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/religion-for-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/religion-for-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Link You can access the channel here: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCct9aR7HC79Cv2g-9oDOTLw</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Religions Paradigm</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/world-religions-paradigm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/world-religions-paradigm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When the category of religion is used to describe &amp;lsquo;world religions&amp;rsquo;, it is often in a way that turns multiple diverse traditions, philosophies, and practices, into one single entity for the sake of simplicity.
A good example of this is Hinduism, which is a label coined by the British to describe the religion of the Indian people.
The hidden diversity of Hinduism
Hinduism did not exist in the language of the Indian peoples (in fact there are many languages in use on the Indian subcontinent); it was a label applied by British observers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BASR 2020 Worldviews in RS and RE Panel</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/basr-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/basr-2020/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  This panel, curated by Wendy Dossett (University of Chester), discusses the Commission for Religious Education’s proposal for a shift towards studying “Religion and Worldviews” in Secondary Religious Education. Contributions from Wendy Dossett, Rudi Eliott Lockhart (former CEO of the Religious Education Council of England and Wales), Suzanne Owen (Leeds Trinity University), Paul-Francois Tremlett (Open University) and Malory Nye (Independent Academic affiliated to University of Glasgow).
 Link You can access the video here: www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rejected Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/rejected-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/rejected-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  What is meant by &amp;ldquo;rejected&amp;rdquo; in Rejected Religion? Put simply, it&amp;rsquo;s everything that has been considered &amp;lsquo;heretical&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;forbidden&amp;rsquo; by the dominant religions throughout Western history. Think of terms such as &amp;lsquo;the occult&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;the esoteric&amp;rsquo; and all that can be located in that area - magical practices such as witchcraft; alternate worldviews such as Satanism; systems such as astrology and tarot; the use of hallucinogenic substances for &amp;lsquo;spiritual&amp;rsquo; growth; or well-known people such as Aleister Crowley &amp;ndash; this is just a small sample of the larger &amp;lsquo;esoteric&amp;rsquo; category that this platform addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journal of Religion, Nature and Culture</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/journal-religion-nature-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/journal-religion-nature-culture/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Link You can access the journal here: https://journals.equinoxpub.com/index.php/JSRNC/index</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Religion Matters: Religious Literacy, Culture and Diversity</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/why-religion-matters-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/why-religion-matters-course/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Link You can access the course here: https://www.futurelearn.com/courses/why-religion-matters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is religious literacy?</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-literacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/what-is-religious-literacy/</guid>
      <description>Religious literacy is a term that has become more popular in recent years, but what exactly do we mean when we talk about it?
The word &amp;lsquo;literacy&amp;rsquo; definitely sounds like it has something to do with reading and understanding written texts - religious traditions will often (but not always!) write things down, so is religious literacy the ability to read these texts?
Nope!
Just like how being able to read is a skill that you can apply throughout your life, religious literacy is a skill that allows you to understand and interpret religious phenomena wherever you encounter them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing World Religions</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/introducing-world-religions-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/introducing-world-religions-2008/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Study of Religion: An Introduction to Key Ideas and Methods</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/the-study-of-religion-an-introduction-to-key-ideas-and-methods-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/s/the-study-of-religion-an-introduction-to-key-ideas-and-methods-2007/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>