<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scripture on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/scripture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scripture on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/scripture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Literary Bias</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/literary-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/literary-bias/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Texts (of all kinds) are controlled and mediated by people, and therefore restrictions can sometimes be made about which texts are preserved and shared, and which are ignored or destroyed. This can lead to an erasure of certain material from a religious tradition, or from the public understanding of that tradition, particularly if the material disagrees with the perspective of those in positions of power.&#xA;Writing in Introducing World Religions, Victoria Kennick Urubshurow discusses three types of erasure: literary bias, marginalised voices, and a combination of the two, where a strong focus on a particular piece or style of literature perpetuates a pre-existing social inequality (2008, p.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Texts</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/text/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Although the word &amp;rsquo;texts&amp;rsquo; might imply a written document, the term has a wider scope in the field of religious studies. We can consider four categories of texts:&#xA;Written documents. The most easily recognised form of text, for example the Bible or the Qur&amp;rsquo;an. Though often considered &amp;lsquo;fixed&amp;rsquo; and unchanging, written texts are frequently altered and edited over long periods, and alternate versions of the same text are sometimes purged to create the image of uniformity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
