<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perspectives on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/categories/perspectives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perspectives on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/categories/perspectives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Dimensions of Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/seven-dimensions-of-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/seven-dimensions-of-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The seven dimensions of religion are a framework for exploring and understanding religion, developed by the Scottish scholar of religion, Ninian Smart.
Smart&amp;rsquo;s approach sidestepped the issue of agreeing on what counted as &amp;lsquo;a religion&amp;rsquo;, and instead identified types of experience and expression that were demonstrably religious or spiritual in nature.
This modular approach to religious studies facilitated a much broader scope to consider and compare spiritual traditions and artefacts from around the world that may not have aligned with a Western conception of what a religion was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liquid Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/liquid-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/liquid-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In looking at religion (or religioning) in the modern world, some scholars have argued that industrial nations have tended to become less religious and more secular. The so-called secularisation theory argues that this will continue, until religion drops off and is forgotten – the roles and purposes served by religion will eventually be replaced by communities or the larger nation state.
However, the secularisation theory seems to be proven false by the complexity of religious change in contemporary societies around the world – yes, larger organised religions have seen a drop in numbers, but people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be less religious or spiritually inclined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Religions Paradigm</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/world-religions-paradigm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/world-religions-paradigm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction When the category of religion is used to describe &amp;lsquo;world religions&amp;rsquo;, it is often in a way that turns multiple diverse traditions, philosophies, and practices, into one single entity for the sake of simplicity.
A good example of this is Hinduism, which is a label coined by the British to describe the religion of the Indian people.
The hidden diversity of Hinduism
Hinduism did not exist in the language of the Indian peoples (in fact there are many languages in use on the Indian subcontinent); it was a label applied by British observers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/alternative-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/alternative-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Alternative perspectives, due to their absence in mainstream texts and dismissal by historical scholars, are sometimes difficult to hear over the sound of traditional narratives – but this is increasingly changing for the better. Where we can open ourselves to these voices, we can improve our understanding of the history of religion, but also our understanding of contemporary religious practitioners as well.
Female academic perspectives on religious literature, contesting or challenging male interpretations, have been developing over a long period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literary Bias</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/literary-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/literary-bias/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Texts (of all kinds) are controlled and mediated by people, and therefore restrictions can sometimes be made about which texts are preserved and shared, and which are ignored or destroyed. This can lead to an erasure of certain material from a religious tradition, or from the public understanding of that tradition, particularly if the material disagrees with the perspective of those in positions of power.
Writing in Introducing World Religions, Victoria Kennick Urubshurow discusses three types of erasure: literary bias, marginalised voices, and a combination of the two, where a strong focus on a particular piece or style of literature perpetuates a pre-existing social inequality (2008, p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capitalist Spirituality</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/capitalist-spirituality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/capitalist-spirituality/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/self-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/self-religion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive Theories</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/cognitive-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/cognitive-theories/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lived Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/lived-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/lived-religion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The concept of &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; has been abstracted from observations of behaviour and experience, but no one can point to &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; as a real thing. Instead, scholars argue, we should talk about people religioning, doing religion, behaving religiously.
This attitude towards religion sees it as a process, not a static entity, and tries to counteract the tendency to bundle complex cultural phenomena into simple ideas - this tendency, when applied to foreign cultures and traditions can be particularly damaging for our understanding of religion, and has contributed to the world religions paradigm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Animism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/new-animism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/new-animism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenomenology</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/phenomenology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/phenomenology/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Material Religion</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/material-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/material-religion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>