<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anthropology on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/anthropology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anthropology on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/tags/anthropology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mary Douglas</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/mary-douglas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/mary-douglas/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Dame Mary Douglas, DBE FBA (25 March 1921 – 16 May 2007) was a British anthropologist, known for her writings on human culture and symbolism, whose area of speciality was social anthropology. Douglas was considered a follower of Émile Durkheim and a proponent of structuralist analysis, with a strong interest in comparative religion.&#xA;Wikipedia</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robin Horton</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/robin-horton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/robin-horton/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Robin Horton (1932 - 2019), an English social anthropologist and philosopher, has carried out specialised study in comparative religion since the 1950s which has challenged and expanded views in the study of the anthropology of religion. He is notable for his comparison of traditional thought systems (including religion) to Western science.&#xA;Wikipedia</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dimitris Xygalatas</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/dimitris-xygalatas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/dimitris-xygalatas/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I am an anthropologist and cognitive scientist studying ritual, cooperation, and some of the things that make us human.&#xA;After receiving my PhD from the Institute of Cognition and Culture at Queen’s University Belfast, I held positions at the universities of Princeton, Aarhus, and Masaryk, where I served as Director of the Laboratory for the Experimental Research of Religion (LEVYNA). In 2014, I joined the University of Connecticut, where I direct the Experimental Anthropology Lab.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ronald Grimes</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ronald-grimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ronald-grimes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ron Grimes is co-editor of the Oxford Ritual Studies Series, Director of Ritual Studies International, and the author of several books on ritual, including The Craft of Ritual Studies. He is Professor Emeritus in the Department of Religion and Culture at Wilfrid Laurier University in Waterloo, Canada. He has held the following positions: Senior Researcher and Senior Lecturer at Yale University; Visiting Professor of Religious Studies at Charles University in Prague; and Chair of Ritual Studies at Radboud University in the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
