<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concepts on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/categories/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/categories/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/community/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Communities can be inward looking, or reach out to the wider world.
Religion not only involves beliefs and practices, it also generally involves participation in a community, which provides a sense of belonging and identity for adherents.
Community can take an institutional form, for instance membership in a church congregation, or it can be a sense of belonging to a less organised, wider group, like the Islamic ummah or community, which includes Muslims from all backgrounds, nations, and theological schools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akashic records</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/akashic-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/akashic-records/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/belief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/belief/</guid>
      <description>Believing in the unseen One of the most prominent and well-known aspects of religion in the Western world is faith. This term often comes with a variety of associated meanings and implications, but at its root we can say that faith involves belief in a set of doctrines or creeds which provide meaning and direction, often in the absence of empirical evidence.
Since the relationship between religious belief and scientific empiricism has often been contentious, it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile looking a little more closely at how people believe in things, and what this means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henotheism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/henotheism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/henotheism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Henotheism means the worship and veneration of one god, in a world where many gods exist – for example the worship of Artemis within the Greek Pantheon.
Image Credits Banner Trevi Fountain, Rome (wikipedia page). Photo by Christopher Czermak on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>