<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concepts on Understanding Religion</title>
    <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/categories/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Understanding Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/categories/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seva</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/seva/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/seva/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Within the Sikh religion, one of the important practical aspects is seva or selfless service, which takes the form of charitable actions.
One of the primary barriers between Sikhs and God is haumai or self-centredness, which prevents the individual from realising their dependence on Waheguru. Seva therefore serves multiple purposes: helping those in the community, building charitable networks, and undermining any grandiose ideas of self-importance.
One example of seva in practice is langar, a shared meal where all visitors to the Gurdwara eat together sitting on the floor, with no regard to hierarchy or background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/community/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Communities can be inward looking, or reach out to the wider world.
Religion not only involves beliefs and practices, it also generally involves participation in a community, which provides a sense of belonging and identity for adherents.
Community can take an institutional form, for instance membership in a church congregation, or it can be a sense of belonging to a less organised, wider group, like the Islamic ummah or community, which includes Muslims from all backgrounds, nations, and theological schools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akashic records</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/akashic-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/akashic-records/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kashrut</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/kashrut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/kashrut/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kosher</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/kosher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/kosher/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ritual</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/ritual/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Religious practices include a wide variety of activity, but in some cases these practices might be described as rituals, a term that carries many conflicting associations. We can look at ritual as a type of religious practice, which pays attention to not only what is done, but also the broader context in which the action is situated.
In other words, rituals are religious practices with some degree of specificity that separates them from ‘everyday’ religious activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/animism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/animism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Animism is a category of religious systems in which human activity is understood within a broader context of persons and their relationships; these persons may include visible beings such as humans, animals, plants, and rocks, and non-visible beings such as spirits or ancestors.
New animism is differentiated from &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; animism by its focus on relational ontologies - ways of being in the world which hinge on relationships, thus taking a more nuanced approach to the subject than historical efforts, which typically centered on the belief in souls which inhabit material bodies and natural phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belief</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/belief/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/belief/</guid>
      <description>Believing in the unseen One of the most prominent and well-known aspects of religion in the Western world is faith. This term often comes with a variety of associated meanings and implications, but at its root we can say that faith involves belief in a set of doctrines or creeds which provide meaning and direction, often in the absence of empirical evidence.
Since the relationship between religious belief and scientific empiricism has often been contentious, it&amp;rsquo;s worthwhile looking a little more closely at how people believe in things, and what this means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brahman</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/brahman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/brahman/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dharma</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/dharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/dharma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henotheism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/henotheism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/henotheism/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Henotheism means the worship and veneration of one god, in a world where many gods exist – for example the worship of Artemis within the Greek Pantheon.
Image Credits Banner Trevi Fountain, Rome (wikipedia page). Photo by Christopher Czermak on Unsplash</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monotheism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/monotheism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/monotheism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panpsychism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/panpsychism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/panpsychism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pantheism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/pantheism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/pantheism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polytheism</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/polytheism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/polytheism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Articles of Faith</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/six-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/six-articles/</guid>
      <description>The Islamic principle of Iman, or faith, is composed of six items, which Muslims are expected to believe in order to live a devout life:
 Allah - the existence of one god, who alone created and sustains the universe Angels - messengers of Allah who can communicate with humanity Holy Books - the scriptures, including the Qur&amp;rsquo;an but also elements of the Tanakh (Hebrew Bible) and the message preached by Isa (Jesus) Prophets - the messengers and prophets of Allah who came before Muhammad Day of Judgement - a day on which Allah will assess the character of each person and either send them to heaven or hell Predestination - Allah knows everything that will happen, although the common view is that humans still have free will to make choices  References to these six articles of faith are frequently made in Islamic publications - for example, take a look at this information page from the Enfield Islamic Centre&amp;rsquo;s website and see if you can find where the articles are mentioned: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trimurti</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/trimurti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/trimurti/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trinity</title>
      <link>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/trinity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.understandingreligion.org.uk/p/trinity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>